[{"question": "What is the need for a File when you can store anything in memory.?", "option1": "A) Memory (RAM) is limited in any computer.", "option2": "B) A file is stored on Hard Disk which can store Gigabytes of data.", "option3": "C) File stored on Hard Disk is safe even if PC is switched off. But Memory or RAM contents are cleared when PC is off.", "option4": "D) All the above", "ans": "D"}, {"question": "What is the keyword used to declare a C file pointer.?", "option1": "A) file", "option2": "B) FILE", "option3": "C) FILEFP", "option4": "D) filefp", "ans": "B"}, {"question": "What is a C FILE data type.?", "option1": "A) FILE is like a Structure only", "option2": "B) FILE is like a Union only", "option3": "C) FILE is like a user define int data type", "option4": "D) None of the above", "ans": "A"}, {"question": "Where is a\u00a0file temporarily stored before read or write operation in C language.?", "option1": "A) Notepad", "option2": "B) RAM", "option3": "C) Hard disk", "option4": "D) Buffer", "ans": "D"}, {"question": "Choose a correct statement about C file operation program.?\nint main()\n{\n    FILE *fp;\n    char ch;\n    fp=fopen(\"readme.txt\",\"r\");\n    while((ch=fgetc(fp)) != EOF)\n    {\n        printf(\"%c\",ch);\n    }\n}", "option1": "A) FOPEN opens a file named readme.txt in Read Mode (\"r).", "option2": "B) EOF is End Of File. ch==EOF checks for end of file and while loop stops or exits.", "option3": "C) FGETC(fp) is a function that returns one character and cursor goes to next character.", "option4": "D) All the above", "ans": "D"}, {"question": "What is the need for closing a file in C language.?", "option1": "A) fclose(fp) closes a file to release the memory used in opening a file.", "option2": "B) Closing a file clears Buffer contents from RAM or memory.", "option3": "C) Unclosed files occupy memory and PC hangs when on low memory.", "option4": "D) All the above", "ans": "D"}, {"question": "If a FILE pointer is NULL what does it mean.?\nFILE *fp;\nfp=fopen(\"abc.txt\",\"w\");\n", "option1": "A) Unable to open a file named abc.txt", "option2": "B) abc.txt is not available on disk", "option3": "C) Hard disk has hard ware problems.", "option4": "D) All the above", "ans": "D"}, {"question": "Choose a correct statement about FGETS in C program.?\nint main()\n{\n    FILE *fp;\n    char str[80];\n    fp=fopen(\"readme.txt\",\"r\");\n    while(fgets(str,80,fp) != NULL)\n    {\n        printf(\"%s\",str);\n    }\n    fclose(fp);\n}", "option1": "A) str in fgets() is a like a user buffer that can store 80 characters each time", "option2": "B) FGETS returns null if no characters are left", "option3": "C) fgets() reads content from File. FPUS writes content back to File.", "option4": "D) All the above", "ans": "D"}, {"question": "Choose a correct statement about C file \"R\" mode operation using fopen.\nfopen(\"abc.txt\",\"r\");", "option1": "A) If the file abc.txt is found, fopen returns a FILE pointer.", "option2": "B) If the file abc.txt is not found, fopen returns NULL or 0.", "option3": "C) File abc.txt is only opened in Read Mode. Now write operation is performed.", "option4": "D) All the above", "ans": "D"}, {"question": " Choose a correct statement about File Write Mode \"w\".\nFile *fp;\nfp=fopen(\"abc.txt\",\"w\");", "option1": "A) If the file abc.txt is not found File abc.txt is created on disk.", "option2": "B) If the file abc.txt is found, fopen() returns a FILE pointer as usual. Every time, contents of abt.txt are overwritten in \"w\" mode.", "option3": "C) Read operation is not allowed in \"w\" mode.", "option4": "D) All the above", "ans": "D"}, {"question": " Choose a correct statement about C File Mode \"w+\".\nFILE *p;\np=fopen(\"abc.txt\",\"r+\");", "option1": "A) r+ mode allows reading of existing contents of file abc.txt only if file is found.", "option2": "B) If file is not found, NULL is returned by fopen().", "option3": "C) You can read existing contents, edit existing content and add new content.", "option4": "D) All the above", "ans": "D"}, {"question": " Choose a correct statement about C file mode \"w+\".\nFILE *fp;\nfp=fopen(\"abc.txt\",\"w+\");", "option1": "A) Like \"w\" mode, \"w+\" mode creates a new file abc.txt if not found. NULL is only returned if some other problems in PC exist in opening a file.", "option2": "B) w+ mode allows you to read the file also. Only after writing, you can read contents if any written. Before writing existing contents are emptied.", "option3": "C) w+ mode always makes a file contents empty like w mode.", "option4": "D) All the above", "ans": "D"}, {"question": " Choose a correct statement about C file mode \"a\".\nFILE *fp;\nfp=fopen(\"abc.txt\",\"a\");", "option1": "A) \"a\" is for append operation. You can append or add new content to the existing contents.", "option2": "B) If file is not found, new file is created.", "option3": "C) You can not write read file contents.", "option4": "D) All the above", "ans": "D"}, {"question": " Choose a correct statement about C file mode \"a+\".\nFILE *fp;\nfp=fopen(\"abc.txt\",\"a+);", "option1": "A) a+ mode always appends new data to the end of existing content", "option2": "B) a+ mode creates a new file if not found or existing.", "option3": "C) a+ mode allows reading also. mode \"a\" allows only appending not reading.", "option4": "D) All the above", "ans": "D"}, {"question": " Choose a correct statement about opening a file in binary mode for reading.\nFILE *fp;\nfp=fopen(\"abc.txt\",\"rb\");", "option1": "A) rb mode opens the file in binary mode", "option2": "B) Binary mode is just reading or writing in bytes instead of integers, characters or strings.", "option3": "C) Binary mode saves memory occupied by contents.", "option4": "D) All the above", "ans": "D"}, {"question": " What is the syntax for writing a file in C using binary mode.?\nFILE *fp;", "option1": "A) fp=fopen(\"abc.txt\",\"wr\");", "option2": "B) fp=fopen(\"abc.txt\",\"wb\");", "option3": "C) fp=fopen(\"abc.txt\",\"wbin\");", "option4": "D) fp=fopen(\"abc.txt\",\"b\");", "ans": "B"}, {"question": " What are the C functions used to read or write a file in Text Mode.?", "option1": "A) fprintf(), fscanf()", "option2": "B) fread(), fwrite()", "option3": "C) fprint(), fscan()", "option4": "D) read(), write()", "ans": "A"}, {"question": " What are the C\u00a0functions used to read or write a file in Binary Mode.?", "option1": "A) fprintf(), fscanf()", "option2": "B) fread(), rwrite()", "option3": "C) readf(), writef()", "option4": "D) printf(), scanf()", "ans": "B"}, {"question": " What is the C\u00a0function used to\u00a0move current pointer to the beginning of file.?\nFILE *fp;", "option1": "A) rev(fp)", "option2": "B) rewind(fp)", "option3": "C) rew(fp)", "option4": "D) wind(fp)", "ans": "B"}, {"question": " Choose a correct syntax for FSCANF and FPRINTF in c language.?", "option1": "A) fprintf(\"format specifier\",variables, fp);\nfscanf(\"format specifier\",variables, fp);", "option2": "B) fprintf(fp,count,\"format specifier\",variables);\nfscanf(fp,count,\"format specifier\",variables);", "option3": "C) fprintf(fp,\"format specifier\",variables);\nfscanf(fp,\"format specifier\",variables);", "option4": "D) None of the above", "ans": "C"}]
